悔しい 悔しい 悔しい
He hates it!
だが これでいい
But it's enough!
これでこそ博打
This is gambling!
Kaiji's sleeping instincts catch fire!
カイジの眠っていた本能に
火がつく
Shards of Fate
To an observer, Kaiji's wager must have seemed like a move made of sheer desperation.
端から見れば なかば
やけになっているとしか思えない
カイジの張り
事実 せきを切ったように
カイジは沈んでいく
Truly, Kaiji sank beneath a flood of emotion.
But at the same time, something awakened within him!
しかし同時にカイジの中に
何かが目覚めていく
He risks it all on that awakening!
その目覚めに賭ける
沈みつつも意地の3000張り
Even as he sinks, he clings to a wager of 3,000!
熱く張り続けて40分後
40 minutes after he's begun betting in earnest.
Kaiji makes another decision.
カイジ　再び決断
He lays on the Perica--his first bet of 5,000!
さらにペリカを重ね
バツの5000張り
And soon, it pays off!
そしてついに それに呼応する
4-5-6! It pays double!
シゴロ　倍づけ
おお！
It appears...
表れるカイジの熱が
ついに宿らしめる
Kaiji's spark has caught aflame!
サイに幸運を
このひと張りで１万の収入
Lady Luck smiles on his dice!
In one roll, he receives 10,000!
Kaiji, whose stack had shrunken to 28,000, is reborn!
２万8000まで落ち込んだカイジ
復活
Back to 38,000!
３万8000へ
And...
そして ここで親番
Now, he deals!
This is it.
来た　ここだ
ここで受けずして いつ受ける
It's now or never.
I'll deal this time.
この親を受ける　さあ張ってくれ
Come on and bet.
Come on.
さあ
しかし
But the others, sensing Kaiji's aggression, each make small bets!
カイジの攻勢を
見て取ったみんなは
そろいもそろって小張り
勝負にはいかない　小張りの連続
A series of pointlessly small bets!
フフフ… そりゃないよな
カイジ君
It's just not your day, huh, Kaiji?
せっかく盛り上がって
受けた親なのに
You finally decide to deal, and then nothing.
But I understand why they don't want to bet, too.
とはいえ ここは
いきたくないという
皆の衆の気持ちも分かる
困ったな
It's too bad.
Oh well, I'll take you on.
ま 仕方ない　わしがやるか
カイジ君 初親の景気づけ
To celebrate your first deal, I'll make a big bet.
祝儀代わりに大張りを
20,000 Perica!?
２万ペリカ…
じゃあ俺も
Me too, then.
These guys...
こいつら　待ってやがったのか
Have they been waiting for me to deal?
俺が親を受けるのを
They're trying to wipe me out in one round!
１発で俺を潰しに来た
They each bet 20,000.
２人が２万　計４万張り
Together, that's a bet of 40,000!
I only have 38,000.
俺の手持ちは３万8000
If I lose, I can't pay.
ここで負けたら
この４万は払えない
I'll have to borrow.
となると当然 借金
Borrow just to cover it!
かぶせるように借金
借金地獄
Debt hell!
いやいや　こりゃ悪かった
Sorry.
I thought I'd liven things up, but everyone's quieted down.
盛り上げるつもりが
少しシーンとさせちまったようだ
しかし最初に説明したとおり
Just as I said from the start, though, 20,000 is this table's maximum wager.
１人２万は この賭場の正規の上限
No problem, right?
何の問題もない
問題が起こるとしたら この後さ
If there's a problem, it'll come after the roll.
サイを振って
カイジ君が勝てばいいんだが
I hope you win.
Because if you lose...
万が一 負けた時は 事よ
If my count is correct, you don't have 40,000.
わしの計算じゃ
今 カイジ君の手持ちは
４万に届いてない　だろ？
Am I right?
Yeah.
ああ
フフフ　となりゃ
Then, let me give it to you straight about how things work down here.
ここは後でモメないように
この地下の取り決めを
伝えておかないとな
To put it bluntly, it's about those loans.
早い話が借金
給料前貸しの取り決めだ
How the payday loans work!
もしカイジ君が負けて
４万を払うハメになったら
If you lose, and have to pay the 40,000...
わしら カイジ君に
給料の前借りを強要する
Then you'll be forced to take another advance.
You see?
でだ ここからが問題なんだが
The problem is...
すでにカイジ君には
来月分の給料を前貸し済みだから
Kaiji, you've already taken an advance on next month's salary.
今度 貸す金は翌々月分の給料の
前貸しとなる
So this will need to come out of your paycheck for the month after that.
ま 翌月でもカイジ君が
重労働に耐え切れず
Considering the risk of you working yourself to death...
ぶっ倒れるリスクも考え
Normally, you receive 60,000 up front...
正規の給料の９万ではなく
６万を払っているんだから
But for two months in advance, I'll need a larger cut.
翌々月となれば
必然的に こちらとしては
さらに払うわけにはいかなくなる
言いにくいんだが
ここは心を鬼にして伝えないとな
It hurts to say this, but...
For two months in advance, you'll get half your check.
翌々月分の前貸しは
正規の９万の半分
Kaiji's advance will be 45,000!
カイジへの前貸し ４万5000
Everyone here's okay with it.
そういうことで ここの皆の衆には
納得してもらってる
Don't blame me, all right?
悪く思わんでくれ フフフ
フッ なるほど
I see.
こりゃ見損なってたぜ
I was wrong.
You're a total dick.
大した悪党じゃないか あんた
60,000? 45,000? Are you shitting me?
よく言うぜ
何が６万 ４万5000だ
You're like an antlion, setting up his muddy pit!
勝手にアリ地獄
泥沼みたいな制度を作っといて
Everyone here's okay with it?
｢皆の衆には
納得してもらってる｣だ？
Idiot!
バカ野郎　その前借り生活から
抜けるには
To get out of that hole, someone needs to go two whole months without food!
２ヵ月を無休で乗り切らなきゃ
ならないんだ
だが 一度飲み食いを覚えたら
もう不可能
But the memory alone makes it impossible!
理不尽と思っても
毎月 給料日になると
But on payday, unreasonable as it may be, you'll take it all!
たぶん受け取っちまう
そして ずっとずっと
受け取り続ける
And you just keep taking that 45,000!
目減りした４万5000をな
クッ これは体のいい
ピンハネじゃねえか
It's nothing but a kickback to you!
今にして思えば
あのちんけなビールの
That shitty beer and junk food is the same!
差し入れからしてそうだ
まず狙った標的の欲望を刺激し
You work someone's hunger up...
金を使わせ 最終的には
このギャンブルに巻き込む
Get them to spend their money...
Then drag them into this game!
いるんだよな そんな人間
I didn't think anyone could be that terrible of a person.
You work alongside us down here... You share our fate...
こんな地下で共に働く
同じように追い詰められた仲間
You steal our pennies and drain us of our blood!
そんな仲間の細い金に取りつく
生き血をすする
You're a leech!
ヒルみたいな人間がよ
Aw man.
参ったな
みんなの便宜を考えてやった
サービスだが
I try to make everyone's life a little happier, and this is the thanks I get?
こんな見当違いの非難を
浴びてしまうとは
Kaiji. I'm your boss. Your business is my business.
カイジ君　いくらみんなの世話を
焼くのが務めの班長とはいえ
わしだって
ただで尽くすわけにはいかんさ
I can't just back off.
いくばくかの見返りは
もらわんと　だろ？
So I need a little something in exchange, you know?
Now, go ahead and roll. We can't get started until the dealer rolls.
さあ振ってくれ　親のカイジ君が
振らないと勝負は始まらない
And hey, if you win, there's no problem at all!
なあに　カイジ君が勝てば
何の問題もない
You all knew, didn't you.
知ってたんだろ？あんたら
えっ？
That we were playing tonight to break me.
この賭場は
俺を落とす賭場だってことを
隣の新入り三好は ともかく
I don't know about Miyoshi here, but the rest of you all knew.
他の連中は みんな知っていた
You knew, and you said nothing.
知っていて黙っていた
Not a thing.
何のことはない
みんな消極的とはいえ
You're all so set in your ways that you support him.
この班長に協力してたってわけだ
Even as you grumble about his control.
ほんとは班長の強権に
不満 不平を抱いてるくせによ
You're afraid of his glare, and you go along.
そのくせ睨まれるのが怖くて
仕方なく協力する
そんな奴らは大嫌いだ
I hate people like you.
班長も許せねえが
I won't forgive him, but I won't forgive slimy bastards like you, either!
そういうどっちつかずの
ぬらぬらした奴らも許せねえ
Who are you expecting to lose?
誰が負けるか
俺は勝つ！
I'll win!
I'll win, right here!
ここで ここで勝つ
負けるわけにはいかない
I can't lose!
Win or lose... There is no other way!
天地　勝つと負けるじゃ天地
If I lose, I'll sink deeper and deeper into the abyss!
負ければ この地下の底の底で
さらに搾り取られる
With half my pay forfeited, I'll be nothing more than a slave!
給料の半分もピンハネされて
まさに奴隷
I'll sink! Sink to the bottom!
沈む　このまま沈んじまう
But if I win...
しかし勝てば 勝てば４万
It's 40,000! I'll have 78,000!
手持ちの合計は７万8000になる
I can pay back the 60,000 I borrowed!
となれば借りた６万を
班長に叩き返しても
And have 18,000 left!
まだ１万8000残る
I can start over! I can see!
やり直せる　目指せる
あの１日外出券を
The hope of the one-day furlough...
rests on one roll of the dice!
サイの目１つで
Damn it!
クソ クソ クソ
God damnit!
Why do I always end up like this!?
なんでいつもこうなるんだ 俺は
いつもそんな役割ばかり
こんな地下地獄に落ちたのは
These tasks...
I'm only down here because I cosigned a loan!
元はといえば保証人を頼まれて
断り切れなかったからだ
But...
だが 落ちたら落ちたで
Even down here, they're after me!
こんな奴らに標的にされる
Shit!
クソ！
目は５
おお！
He rolls a five!
よし　まずまず
そうさ　今 俺は上り調子
All right! That's a start!
Things are looking up for me now!
Nothing's gone wrong yet.
下手な目は まず出ないはずなんだ
当然だ この結果は
Of course I'd roll something good.
Looks like you've dug your own grave, boss.
潰すつもりが
とんだ墓穴を掘ったな 班長
Yes! In chinchirorin, a five is a good, strong roll!
そう　チンチロにおける５の目は
相当強い いい目である
The odds of any roll but triples or 4-5-6 is the same,
目の出る確率は
ぞろ目 シゴロを除けば
どの数字でも同じ108分の15
15 out of 108!
だが５に勝つのは６しかない
But only a six can defeat a five!
The odds of a one through four are four out of six!
１から４が出る確率は６の４倍
目なしを入れれば
その確率はもっと高くなる
Add in busts, and the odds are even better!
５は９割近く
負けを知らぬ目と言っていい
A five stands merely a ten percent chance of losing!
Aww jeez...
あっちゃー
事実 三好以下は
軒並みカイジの５に屈し
Indeed, one by one, beginning with Miyoshi, the players lose!
３連敗
そして いよいよ２万張りの１人
And then the bowl passes to the first bet of 20,000, the boss's lackey, Isawa!
班長側の石和にどんぶりが回る
No other roll matters to Kaiji now!
カイジにとって今
他の張りなど どうでもいい
The only things that matter are the rolls of this man and the boss!
問題は班長大槻と この男の振り
Isawa makes his fateful first roll!
石和 注目の第１投
目は４
よし
He rolls a four!
All right!
よしよし まずは１勝
That's it! It starts with a victory!
どうぞ
うん
Here.
Next, the boss, Ohtsuki!
続いて班長大槻
出るな　出てたまるか
He won't get it! He can't get it!
５以上の目など
Nothing over five!
再び４　班長側２連敗
Another four!
The boss's side fails twice!
I... I... I did it!
や… や… やった！
I did it I did it I did it!
やった やった やった
カイジさん
よし 生き残った　生き残ったぞ
Kaiji!
All right! I'm still alive! I'm still alive!
I win!
俺の勝ち　復活だ 復活
I'm back! I'm back!
ついに はい上がった
借金漬けのピンハネ地獄
Kaiji rises from the hell of debt!
これで また目指せる
His eyes reopen!
あの１日外出券を
To the one-day furlough!
Excuse me.
失礼します
珍しいよな
班長が大勝負に負けるの
Huh, the boss doesn't normally lose when it's on the line.
結局 沼川を含め班長側は３連敗
In the end, counting Numakawa, the boss's side loses three in a row!
その後の子も ことごとく
カイジの５を上回れず
None of the remaining players can beat Kaiji's five, either!
Kaiji wins every match as dealer!
カイジ　この親 全勝
うひょー！ハハハ
悪いな みんな　悪いな
では遠慮なく
Sorry about that, guys! I'll be taking all of this!
おい
はい
Hey.
Here.
どうぞ
うん
へっ サイひと振りで
４万2200の収入
42,200 with a single roll of the dice.
I was losing all night, but now I've turned it around.
負けが込んでいた勝負が
ひと振りで一気に逆転
I'm ahead of the game now.
プラスに持っていった
８万あれば
例の前借り６万を返しても
With 80,000 I can pay him back and still have twenty thou left.
まだ２万残る
班長が いくら俺を潰そうとしても
親さえしのげばいい
All I need to do to get out from under him is survive my turn as dealer.
The players choose their bets, so I can keep my hands to sixty thou easy.
子は張りをｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾙできるから
前借りの６万を残して生き残れる
カイジ君　親は２回
Kaiji. Dealers go twice.
え？
みんな そうしてきたろ？
We've all been doing it.
１回で終わるのは目なしや
ピンの目 ヒフミが出た時だけだ
You only get to quit at one if you roll a one, a bust, or a 1-2-3.
Don't go passing the bowl off yet.
とぼけて回すなよ どんぶりを
ああ… ああ そうか
Oh, right!
Sorry, guys. I wasn't paying attention.
悪い悪い　ついうっかりしてたよ
I wasn't trying to trick you or anything.
いや マジで
ごまかす気なんてねえさ
さあ張ってくれ
今なら負ける気がしねえ
All right, make your bets and make sure you're cool with losing them!
History's gonna repeat itself!
１回も２回も同じことさ
さあ張ってくれ　え？
So, go ahead and bet!
班長たち　再び２万ずつ４万張り
The boss and his lackey each bet 20,000, for a total of 40,000!
Seriously? You're seriously still trying to take me down?
マジかよ　あくまで
潰しに来るってか
Oh, no, we're not after anything like that.
いやいや 潰すとか何とか
そんなんじゃないさ
We just feel like the dice are cooling off for you.
ただ単純に そろそろ
目の下がる頃かと思ってさ
けっ 何を言ってやがる
細い目ギラギラさせやがって
What are you talking about?
You're sitting back there all shifty-eyed! Of course you're trying to break me!
満々じゃねえか 潰す気で
フフフ
けど悪いが見誤ってるぜ
その押し
Sorry, but you're reading us wrong.
You're throwing your money away.
捨て金だ それは
まだ俺には目が出るはずだ
The dice are still gonna come up for me.
フフフ　わしはないと見た
Doesn't look that way to me.
はっ さっさと張れ
Hurry up and bet!
間を空けさせるな
はい
Don't slow things down!
All right...
今なら出る 出る 今なら
They'll come up! I know it!
This time!
今 振れば出る
If I roll, they'll come up!
今 振れば強い目が出る
If I roll now...
I'll roll well!
Here goes.
いくぜ
はい
All right...
Kaiji rolls again!
カイジ　２度振って２度目なし
And again, a bust!
フフフ　な？そろそろ引き潮だろ
Well? Shall I take my money now?
Damn it!
クソ
The three dice can come up 216 different ways!
３個のサイコロの
目の組み合わせは
全部で216通り
Of those, including 1-2-3, there are 108 valid rolls in chinchirorin!
そのうちヒフミを含め108を
チンチロは目と定めている
So the odds of a successful roll are just fifty percent!
つまり１回振って目の出る確率は
ジャスト50パーセント
With three rolls, the odds climb to 87.5%!
３回振れば確率は ぐっと上がって
87.5パーセント
Roll three times, and something will come up nearly 90% of the time!
つまり３回振れば
９割近く目が出る
頼む　出ろ
Please! Come up!
The crucial third roll!
明暗分かつ３投目
Look! A six! I rolled a six!
見ろ　６だ！６だ！
俺の勝ちだ　やった！
I win!
All right!
救われた　ギリギリの最後で
I'm saved! That was a close call!
Saved by that one last bit of luck...
強運の流れ　欠片に
やった やった やった
All riiiiiight!
はしゃぐなよ
え？
Don't get too excited.
まだ確定したわけじゃない
This isn't over yet.
一部　残っている
こっちの勝ち目も
I have one chance left to win.
A chance?
勝ち目？
そうさ
Yeah. In normal chinchiro, your six would end things.
通常のチンチロなら
この６で終わり
The dealer would take all the bets.
親の総取りさ
子はサイを振ることはできない
The players wouldn't even get to roll.
But here, we roll.
だが ここじゃ振れるんだ
振れる以上 どんな小さい確率でも
We roll, and no matter how small the chance is, it's still a chance.
可能性は残されている
If we roll a six like you, it's a draw.
カイジ君の出目と同じ６を出せば
引き分けだし
And if we roll a 4-5-6 or triples, the tables are turned.
もしシゴロやゾロ目を
出したら逆転
逆にこっちの勝ちってわけだ
Then, we win.
だろ？まだ望みは残っている
Right?
A hope still remains.
Really? Is he serious?
マジ？マジに
本気で言ってるわけ？
本気さ　だって事実そうだろ？
Dead serious.
I'm right, aren't I?
へっ バカ　起きねえんだよ
そんなことは
Moron.
There's no way that'll happen!
Sure, if you roll long enough, you'll eventually get triples or a 4-5-6.
そりゃ たくさん握って振りゃ
シゴロもゾロ目も出るさ
だが今まさにここ
But no way in hell are you getting 'em right now.
この瞬間になんて
出たりゃしねえっての
You're not gonna get that lucky.
そんなに都合よくいくわけ
ねえじゃねえか
Even you should be smart enough to figure that out.
分かってんだろ？んなこと
あんただって
You should know that damn well.
腐るほど味わってきたはずだ
Sure, Kaiji.
分かるよ カイジ君
カイジ君の言うことも
You're right.
しかし それでも何というか
わしは信じていてのお
But, I still believe.
念が時に
サイの目を左右することを
Sometimes raw will weighs on the dice.
What?
は？
念力が高めるんだ
When someone's will is unleashed, it can even bring them back from the dead.
起死回生の可能性を
ね… 念力だと？
Willpower!?
You understand, don't you?
分かるかな
分かるかよ んなこと　アハハ
How the hell am I supposed to understand that?
あんましバカバカしくて
ついていけねえよ
That's too retarded for me to follow!
ハハハ　マジ念力かよ
Willpower? Seriously?
そりゃすげえよ　最高だぜ あんた
You're killing me!
You're just perfect!
アハハ　念力？
Willpower...
確かにバカげている　しかし
He does look like a fool.
But.
But! The boss's lackey Isawa makes his roll!
しかし班長側の石和の１投目
シゴロ　倍づけ
A 4-5-6! It pays double!
All right!
おっしゃー！
ヘヘ　２万の倍づけは４万
Double on a 20 thousamd bet is 40 thou.
これでお前の
さっきの勝ちは飛んだ
That's your win before, right there.
手持ち８万は
あっという間に残り４万
From 80 thousand right back down to 40.
バ… バカな
No way!
なんでこんなことが…
Why is this happening!?
And the boss, Ohtsuki!
そして班長大槻
カツ！
Im-Impossible!
まさか… まさか…
カイジ君　博打は恐ろしいな
Gambling is a frightening thing, isn't it, Kaiji?
Really, truly frightening.
ほんとに博打は恐ろしい
The boss Ohtsuki rolls three fives!
班長大槻　なんと５ゾロ
３倍づけ　圧勝
It pays triple! A total victory!
そ… そんなバカな
That's impossible!
How did this happen!?
なんでこんな目が
こんなバカなことが…
This makes no sense!
Sorry, Kaiji, but you're bankrupt.
カイジ君　悪いが
これであんたは破産だ
Triples pay triple, so you owe me 60,000.
５ゾロは３倍づけだから
２万張りは６万払い
You only have 40,000. You can't pay.
カイジ君の手持ち４万では
この６万は補えない
You're short...
あんたマイナス２万！
Twenty thousand!
Kaiji! Kaiji!
カイジさん！カイジさん！
どうして　なんで？
Why? Why!?
こんな こんな
こんな理不尽なことが
Why does this bullshit always happen to me?!
俺のみばかりに…
カイジ 卒倒　地の底の底の底でも
Kaiji passes out!
In the depths of the abyss, he enters debt hell!
借金地獄突入
The CR Gambling Apocalypse Kaiji 2 pachinko machine.
With Restricted Rock-Paper-Scissors, Girders, and E-Card.
A complete record of the Kaiji anime.
Plus, original animation seen only on pachinko machines!
Enjoy the world of red-hot gambles!
Pachinko.
Kaiji 2.